--==本字幕由 HDWinG字幕组 荣誉出品==--
字幕来源：YYeTs字幕组    调校制作：CK@HDWinG
HDWinG字幕组作品   转载请注明出处
本字幕仅供学习交流  严禁用作任何商业盈利行为
《真·探》
第一季  第二集
那会  我想睡觉
Back then, I'd sleep and
却睡不着  一直在想女人
I'd lay awake thinking about women.
我女儿...我妻子
My daughter... my wife.
好像她们身上刻着我的名字
I mean, it's like... something's just got your name on it,
就像一颗子弹
like a, like a bullet
或者马路上的一颗钉子
or a nail in the road.
妈的
Shit.
不好意思  扯远了
Sorry. I drift...
我喝点酒之后老爱瞎扯
sometimes when I've had a few. That's...
所以我才喜欢一个人喝酒
That's why I like to drink alone.
至少是原因之一吧
One reason, anyway.
关于王冠的事
About that sculpture thing.
数年后  就这样出现有点奇怪
Kind of strange it turns up like that years later.
对  没人知道那玩意为什么出现在玩具房
Yeah, nobody knew why that thing was in the playhouse.
证据
她阿姨猜测也许是她
I mean, the aunt reckoned maybe it was something
在学校做的东西
she made in school, you know?
但我看  像是有人
To me, it was like someone was
想表达什么
having a conversation, you know?
92年  那女孩的学校关闭了
Girl's... school shut down in '92.
安德鲁事件之后就关闭了
It closed down after Andrew.
这对你们有用吗
That mean anything to you?
我们通知了死者的母亲
Oh, we notified the deceased's mother.
你还记得上次见到
Do you remember the last time
朵拉的情形吗
you saw your daughter Dora?
那太恐怖了  太恐怖了
It was a horrible, horrible thing.
我们在电视上看到了
We saw it on TV,
我们为之祷告
what we're in the clutches of,
我还为她的家人祈祷
and I prayed and prayed for that woman's family.
结果却是我
And it's me.
是我
It's me.
凯丽夫人
Mrs. Kelly.
那她父亲呢
What about her father?
他们亲吗
Did they have a relationship?
为什么这么问  你们听说了什么
Why? What have you heard?
我听说他过世了  对吗
I heard he passed. Is that correct?
为什么父亲不给自己的孩子洗澡
Why wouldn't a father bathe his own child?
我们只是想知道
We, uh, we were just wondering
他们关系好不好
how they got on, ma'am.
他出车祸死的
He died on the road.
他开的是彼得贝尔卡车
He drove a Peterbilt,
下高速时开得太快
and he took an exit too fast.
在俄克拉荷马州罗宛镇附近翻车了
Rolled over near Rowan, Oklahoma.
1984年  5月11日的事了
May 11, 1984.
你最后一次跟她说话时什么时候
When was the last time you talked to her?
她总是有各种各样的麻烦
You know, she's always been in some kind of trouble.
我原以为事情有所好转
I thought things were getting better.
跟查理分开了
Got away from Charlie.
她不久前来过  大概一月前
She came by not too long ago, maybe a month.
她压根没提到她爸爸
She didn't talk about her daddy none.
只说了她一直去教堂
Said she'd been going to church.
你...
Do you, um,
你记得那教堂在哪里吗
do you remember where that church was?
凯丽女士
Mrs. Kelly?
不
No.
万福玛利亚  满被圣宠者  主与尔偕焉
Hail Mary, full of grace, the Lord is with thee.
万福玛利亚  满被圣宠者
Hail Mary, full of grace.
凯丽女士
Mrs. Kelly--
我头疼
I-- I get these headaches.
疼得要死
It's like storms.
我干了20年干洗
I worked in dry-cleaning for 20 years.
那些化学药剂
The chemicals.
把我指甲搞成这样
That's what's wrong with my nails.
这人不太好搞定
Piece of work, huh?
我母亲是唐娜·里德那样的女人
My mother-- Donna Reed type.
唐娜·里德是美国女演员
其在《唐娜·里德秀》中扮演的角色成为了
美国20世纪50年代最典型的妻子形象
打包午餐
Packed lunches,
讲睡前故事
bedtime stories.
你的母亲还在世吗
Your mom still alive?
可能吧
Maybe.
科尔谈起过他的父母吗
Cohle ever talk about his parents?
没  说过一点关于他父亲的事
No. Little bit about his dad.
阿拉斯加  越南战争之类的
Alaska, 'Nam.
我爸爸  我比他高15厘米
You know, my dad, I had about 6 inches on him,
但哪怕是他弥留的时候
and even in the end,
我都觉得打不过他
I still think he could have taken me.
对  海军陆战队  驻扎在韩国
Yeah, Marines, Korea.
从没跟人说起过这事
Never talked about it.
有那么一阵子
You know, there was a time that
男人们不满嘴跑火车了
men didn't air their bullshit to the world.
突然就不这么做了
You know, it just wasn't a part of their job.
同时...
Well...
家庭
family.
我是说  我...
Well, I mean, I...
我觉得拉斯特的问题  一部分在于
I think a part of Rust's problem was
他明明有需要  却不承认
there was things he needed that he couldn't admit to.
午安  先生
Afternoon, men.
接下来我们找被害人的朋友谈了谈
So we talked to the victim's friend next, I believe.
卡拉小姐吗
Miss Carla?
我以为她一直跟她母亲一起住
I guess she always had her mom's place,
不过  我觉得她可能迷上什么了
but, uh, I thought maybe she'd gotten into somethin',
比如又沉迷赌博了
you know, like, uh, like gamin' again.
过得不太好
Havin' a rough time.
你们平时聊些什么  她是个怎么样的人
What all did y'all talk about? How was she?
瘦瘦的  呆头呆脑
Thin, loopy,
经常嗑药
like high,
每天都迷迷糊糊的
usually on somethin'.
她说她找到了一个教堂  不过...
She says she found a church, but, uh--
她的眼神
her eyes.
有些不对
Something wrong with'em.
你记得那教堂在哪吗
Now, do you remember where this church was?
不
No.
你知道她会待在哪儿吗
You know where she might have been staying?
她的房东说她去年夏天搬走了
Her landlord said she'd moved out last summer.
那时起我就不太见到她了
That's when I stopped seein' her so much.
她提到过在南方
She mentioned someplace down south,
好像在西班牙湖附近  一个...
like around Spanish Lake, a...
庇护所  姑娘们都待在那儿
shelter, girls used to stay there,
之类的  她这么说的
something, all she said.
她听上去很伤心  马蒂
She sounds sad, Marty,
像个垂死之人
like a torn-up person on her last legs.
这种姑娘最容易下手
She was just an easy target for him.
我们对他了解多少
What do we know about him?
袭击妓女  有艺术细胞
Hits prosts, artistic,
有某种宗教信仰
religious in some kind of way.
这方圆几千里
Every person within a thousand miles of here
也就你没有信仰了吧
is religious in some kind of way, except you.
有几个尸体能有鹿角
How many DBs have antlers,
蒙着眼睛
blindfolds,
背上画着符号
painted symbols on their back, hmm?
瘾君子嗑药了什么都敢干
Yeah, you know what tweakers get up to.
该死  新奥尔良有个哥们
Shit, man, this dude in New Orleans
把他女朋友分尸  突然后悔了
cut up his girl, felt remorse,
就又用万能胶粘起来了
tried to piece her back together with Krazy Glue.
这是药物性精神失常
That's just drug insanity.
这不一样  这有针对性
Ah, that's not this. This has scope.
她被装扮成了杀手所看到的异象
Now, she articulated a person with vision.
异象有其意义  意义又有史可稽
Vision is meaning. Meaning is historical.
她本人根本不重要
Look, she was just chum in the water, man.
毫无收获的一天
Days of nothing.
办案的日子就这样
That's what it's like, you work cases.
迷途的羔羊一样
Days like lost dogs.
日子一直那样
Goes on like that.
这工作就那样
You know the job.
探索案件背后的故事
You're looking for narrative,
审问目击者
interrogate witnesses.
起床了  爸爸
Wake up, Daddy.
用各种残缺的证据
Parcel evidence,
建立时间线
establish a timeline,
一点一点  编出一个故事来
and build a story day after day.
不  不
No! No!
那天晚上
Hey, the other night,
你来吃晚饭
when you were over for dinner,
克里斯打来电话之后  你为什么没走
why didn't you leave when I had Chris call?
我不知道
Mmm, I don't know.
可能我稍微清醒一点了
I guess I had sobered up a little.
另外  那也没我想的那么糟
Besides, it wasn't as bad as I thought.
和你的家人在一起
And being around your family,
我喜欢和她们聊天
I liked talking to them.
"糟"  你怎么会这么觉得
"Bad"? Why'd you think that?
我结过婚  马蒂  结婚三年
I was married, Marty, for 3 years.
我们有一个...  女儿
We had a... baby girl.
夭折了
She died.
车祸  她那时两岁
Car accident. She was two years old.
我们的婚姻太脆弱
Marriage couldn't handle it.
你女儿夭折了
Your kid died?
我...
Oh, I...
抱歉  伙计  很抱歉  我不知...
I'm sorry, man. I am so sorry. I didn't--
别这样  不是你们的错  问题在于我
No, I mean, it wasn't you guys. It was just me.
我担心...
I was worried...
就是  接触家庭什么的
you know, being around that kind of thing.
你结过婚吧  就一次
Hey, you were married the once, just the once?
嗯  还有次差点成了
Uh-huh. Came close another time.
和劳瑞
Laurie.
玛姬介绍的
Maggie introduced us,
后来分了
and it-- it broke off.
这样也好  我不怪她
It was for the best, you know. I gave her cause.
和我生活不容易
I can be hard to live with. You know, I...
我总是会不自觉地批评别人
I don't mean to, but I can be... critical.
有时我觉得我就适合独居
And sometimes I think I'm just not good for people,
这是为了我身边的人好
you know, that it's not good for them to be around me.
我  总让他们劳神费心
You know, I... I wear 'em down,
他们就
you know, they...
会不高兴
they get unhappy.
许多干警察的都这样
Yeah, I think the job does that to a lot of guys.
职业改变性格  有些人注意到了  仅此而已
Changes you. Some guys just notice, that's all.
我应该不是干了警察才这样
Well I can't say the job made me this way.
而是这性格让我适合干警察
More like me being this way made me right for the job.
过去我还
And I used to...
常常思考这事
think about it more, but...
但是到了一定的年龄  你自然就了解自己了
you know, you reach a certain age, you know who you are.
现在我住在城外
Now I live in a little room
乡间酒吧后的一间小屋里
out in the country, behind a bar.
每周工作四晚  没事喝喝酒
Work 4 nights a week, in between, I drink,
也没人管我
and there ain't nobody there to stop me.
这才是我
I know who I am.
这么多年
After all these years, there's a...
我才终于明白此事
there's a victory in that.
上班第三天
Third day on the job,
我拦下了一个超速的美女
stopped this cutie for speeding.
52分钟后  我和她就在她宿舍了
52 minutes later, back in her dorm room.
我把我的制服
I got my...
脱到了膝盖那里
uniform around my knees.
我正忙着呢
I'm occupied,
什么也听不到
So I don't hear anything.
我都不知道她室友回来了
I don't know that her roommate has come home
-偷偷溜到我们身后    -糟糕
- and snuck up behind us.   - Oh, shit.
你知道我怎么发现她回来了吗
You know how I knew that she was in the room?
她拿手指爆了我的菊花
She stuck her finger up my ass!
害惨我了  现在不这样都不爽
Ruined me. Now I can't do without it.
这职业也有让人怀念的地方
You miss some things on the job.
你懂的
You know what I mean.
安心过日子之前
You got to... decompress
总得先给自己缓解压力
before you can go being a family man.
当你投入工作时
What you get into working,
就没法兼顾孩子
you can't have the kids around that.
有时需要整理思绪
So, um, sometimes you got to get your head right.
能去你那吗
Mind if I stop by?
那取决于你在哪
I don't know. Where are you?
艾尔克斯
Elks.
那你肯定醉了
So you're drunk.
我没醉
No, I'm not,
我都没怎么喝
and I've hardly had anything to drink.
你老是没怎么喝
You never hardly have anything to drink.
我有惊喜给你
I have a surprise for you.
真的吗
Oh, yeah?
那你是同意了
Is that a yes?
考虑考虑
I, uh, might stay up.
解压对妻子孩子也是好事
It's for your wife and kids, too.
有机会就抓住  赶紧放松
You got to take your release where you find it
有时机会还会送上门
or where it finds you.
这对家庭是有好处的
I mean, in the end, it's for the good of the family.
那是什么
What's that?
是  我
Oh, well, I, uh,
给你的礼物
got you a present.
不要动
Don't move a muscle.
不动  除了指头
I shan't. Just the fingers,
只有指头
the finger muscles.
停下
Oh, stop.
你真不乖
Oh, you're very naughty.
你有权保持沉默
You have the right to remain silent.
你所说的任何话
Anything you say
都将作为呈堂证供
can and will be held against you in a court of law.
你有权聘请律师
You have the right to an attorney.
如果你负担不起
If you can't afford an attorney,
政府将为你指派
the state will provide you one.
明白你的权利了吗
Do you understand your rights?
你都能直接进司法部了
You definitely have a career in law enforcement.
我本来打算给你用的
Well, I thought I was gonna put these on you.
想要吗
You want this?
真的想要
You want it?
能再解释一下吗
Now, what do you mean,
你提到的异象
exactly, these visions you mentioned?
我以为你知道呢
Oh, shit. I thought you knew.
其实我都告诉过马蒂了
I told Marty about them, you know, down the line.
就是记忆闪回
Uh, chemical... flashbacks,
精神创伤那些
neural damage, you know,
我在HIDTA时留下的
from my time in the HIDTA,
就是大规模贩毒区
as in High-Intensity Drug Trafficking Area.
我当过4年的卧底
I spent 4 years undercover.
懂吗
You know what that means?
所以才有了我刚来时的那些流言
That's where they got them Fed rumors, I first come in.
什么  你们俩不知道吗
What, you two don't know about them?
那些文件还封存着是吗
Those files are still sealed, huh?
可恶
Shee-it.
你们俩知道我的什么
Just what have you two heard about me?
你想要蓝色小药丸吗
You wanted blues?
安眠酮
Quaaludes.
-镇定剂吗    -是让人变迟钝的东西
- Downers?   - Dopey stuff.
价格是多少
What's it run?
蓝色小药丸一片三元
I'm thinking blue go for three a pill.
给你200元  我要一瓶
We'll say 200 for the bottle.
我猜到你也许会全都要
I thought you might just take 'em.
或许你想要别的什么
Or that you wanted somethin' else.
别的某件事
Some kind of somethin' else?
不
No.
我在想什么呢  你这么帅
Then I was thinking, you're a good-looking man.
不需要靠勒索就有人愿意跟你干
You wouldn't need a shakedown to get some.
有没有客人比较粗暴或者让人害怕的
What about rough trade, scary guys?
你们女孩子之间应该会聊的
You girls talk.
在这里的人  要么很粗鲁
Around here, they're rough
要么喝了酒就不是人
or whiskey-limp.
见过很多人被激怒
Seen plenty of guys that get touchy.
某件事刺痛了他们
Something sets them off
他们就会像小孩子那样冲动
and they're like little boys.
人们通常会转身离开
People always go away around here.
我应该去哪里找
Where would I look,
可能认识那个金发女孩的人
working girls might know the blonde?
如果她在I-10高速公路南边干过
If she was gaming I-10 south side,
我知道这个地方
I heard of this place.
是个活动住房区一类的地方
Kind of trailer park.
女孩们会留下工作
Girls work and stay.
她们管那里叫大农场
They call it "The Ranch."
在哪里
Where's that?
好像在  西班牙湖的南边  应该是
Like, south of Spanish Lake, supposed to be.
你知道那个地方吗
You know the place?
你的工作是什么
What's your deal?
我没什么条件
I don't have a deal.
我的意思是  你是干什么的
I mean, what do you do?
别在意  我以为你会逮捕我
Never mind. I thought you were gonna bust me.
我跟你说过了  我没兴趣
I told you, I'm not interested.
是的  我知道
Yeah, I know.
有点奇怪  就像你是个危险的人
Kinda strange, like you might be dangerous.
我当然是个危险的人
Well, of course I'm dangerous.
我是警察
I'm police.
我可能会对人做很可怕的事
I could do terrible things to people...
而且还能不受惩罚
with impunity.
你昨晚干什么去了
You know, what'd you do last night?
我晚上过来来着
I called up here late.
你在做什么
What were you doing?
干活
Working.
只是想顺路来看看
Was thinking about dropping by.
你去哪里了
Where were you?
我和女朋友们出去玩
I was out with girlfriends.
我不喜欢这个答案
Uh-huh. Well, I don't like that.
怎么  你嫉妒了吗
What, you're jealous?
别傻了
Don't be stupid.
我是想说外面有个疯子
I just mean that there's a crazy man out there,
他专门杀害女性
and he's killing women.
又是那个女孩吗  那个撒旦印记
Wait, you mean that girl again, that Satanic thing?
法庭里每个人都在说那件事
Everyone's still talking about that at the courthouse.
不只是她
It's not just her.
有更多受害者
There's more.
还有别的受害者  真的吗
There's more? Really?
是的  我们没对其他人说
Yeah, well, we're not saying,
也没向媒体透露  但是
keeping it out of the press, but...
我们认为他多次作案
we're thinking that he's been doing this a while.
是的  暂时别出去了
Yeah, so no need to go out.
你就在这里喝吧
You just have a drink here.
我不能在家里和好男人约会
I can't meet a nice man at home.
你用那种
That hurts me
消极攻击的方式说话是对我的伤害
when you speak to me in a passive-aggressive way.
我对你都是有话就直说
I always talk straight to you.
抱歉  我的意思是你已经结婚了
Excuse me. I meant that since you're married,
作为一个年轻的女人
I need to be considering
我需要重新考虑我的选择了
my options as a young woman.
我想要很多东西  马蒂
I want things, Marty.
我也一样
I want things, too.
没错  你想要你的蛋糕
Yeah, you just want your cake
还要吃掉它
and to eat it, too.
如果不能吃
How good is cake
那蛋糕再美味又有什么意义
if you can't eat it?
早安
Morning.
我想我可能发现了好东西
Hey, I think I might have found something good.
小兔山庄往南
Bunny ranch down south,
西班牙湖附近
round Spanish Lake.
今天不是该找老约翰吗
I thought we were pulling old Johns today.
我们应该先做这件事
Yeah, we should do this first.
怎么了
What?
你去洗洗  你身上有股骚味儿
You wash up. You got some pussy on you.
这是健康婚姻的关键
Key to a healthy marriage.
那是玛姬的吗
Oh, that's Maggie, huh?
你那该死的鼻子又欠打了吗
What's with your fucking nose?
没什么伙计  抱歉  忘记我说的话吧
Nothing, man. Sorry. Forget it.
我觉得你是在暗示
I get a connotation being implied here
我老婆什么
about my wife?
你是想说你带进来的骚味
Are you saying that's wife,
是你老婆的吗
that high tide you're walking in with?
你知道
You got some idea
我老婆的小穴闻起来是什么味儿吗
how my wife's pussy's supposed to smell?
不知道  我的意思是你
No, I just meant you're
穿着和昨天一样的衣服
wearing the same clothes as you did yesterday,
再加上我又不傻
coupled with the fact that I ain't stupid.
并不是要对这气味
Wasn't making no comment as to the...
做任何评论
particularity of the scent.
你他妈的别提我老婆
You don't say fuck-all about my wife.
别提她的名字
Don't say her name.
你瞧不上你自己  那无所谓
You got some self-loathing to do this morning, that's fine,
但是不值得把你的手给搭进去
but it ain't worth losing your hands over.
你想怎么做啊
How would that work, exactly?
我只需要再多施加点压力
Well, I'd just apply a couple pounds of pressure,
就能折断你的手腕
snap your wrists.
你是高级警探
You're Senior Detective.
认为我在虚张声势
Think I'm lying?
你是有这地方的具体地址
You got a specific location for this place
还是我们要瞎逛直到找到它
or are we just gonna wander around till we find it?
我们手里有些人名
We got some names.
我得向他们问问路
I'm gonna have to ask for directions.
或许你闻着味找也行
Maybe you could just follow your nose.
不论他在哪儿找到他们的
Wherever he picked them up,
我不会撒谎的
I mean, I won't lie.
不管最后怎么样
However we left it,
他总能做到些什么
he had some moves.
他以前缉毒的时候认识了几个线人
He knew a few CIs from his narco days.
他们了解这一片  帮我们和一些
They knew these parts, put us in touch
可以打听事儿的人牵线
with some names, people to talk to.
你好
How we doing, boys?
-嗨    -你好
- Hey.   - Hello.
我们在找"小兔山庄"
We're looking for a little Bunny ranch
"月光小兔山庄"是内华达州最负盛名的妓院之一
应该就在这附近
down around these parts.
你们知道哪儿能找到吗
Y'all know where we could find it?
-不知道  先生    -从没听说过
- No, sir.   - Never heard about it?
-妓院    -没有
- Little whorehouse?   - Nuh-uh.
抱歉
Sorry, man.
在这里做木工的都这么趾高气扬的吗
Supposed to be stuck up in the woods around here?
就这么跟你说吧
And I'll tell you this,
拉斯特是我见过的洞悉人性之弱点最厉害的人
Rust had about as sharp an eye for weakness as I ever seen.
我马上就回来
I'll be right back.
我的错
It's my bad, boys.
我们开篇开的不对
Think we got started on the wrong foot there.
记起来妓院在哪里了吗
You remember where that little whorehouse is, huh?
走353南路
Take 353 South.
在到达14号公路之前要下去
Gonna exit off the shoulder before we get to the 14.
然后我们再走条废弃的钓鱼小路去陈纳德河口
From there, we take a dirt fishing road to Bayou Chenault.
好的
Okay.
就是这儿
That it?
警车啊
Cop car, y'all.
去试着要点免费赠品
Just trying to get some freebies.
我不接警察的活
I don't do no cops...
你好  女士
Hello, ma'am.
州立刑事调查局的马丁·哈特和拉斯特·科尔
Martin Hart, Rustin Cohle-- State CID.
这是你的地方
This your place?
是我租的
It's my lease.
这里是什么  某种乡下的"小兔山庄"
What is this, some kind of hillbilly bunny ranch?
你说什么
Excuse me?
在你开始指控我罪名之前
You might want to talk to Sheriff Bilson
你应该先跟拜森治安官谈谈
'fore you start tossin' accusations around.
不用  我跟乡下佬没什么可闹的
No, I ain't got nothing against hillbillies.
别紧张  我不是为这个而来的  我们
Relax. That's not why we're here. We, uh,
有个女孩遇难了
well, something happened to a girl,
我们想知道你们有谁认识她
and we need to know if any of you knew her.
对  这是朵莉
Yeah. That's Dori.
发生什么事了吗
Somethin' happened?
你知道那个在伊拉斯城外发现的女人吗
You know about that woman found outside of Erath?
天哪
Oh, no.
朵莉发生什么事了
Did something happen to Dori?
你们关系很好吗
Were you pretty good friends with her?
我刚来的时候  她对我很友好
She was nice to me when I first came around.
给了我一些建议和东西
Gave me tips and stuff.
建议  关于什么的
Tips? About what?
没什么
Nothing.
你懂的  就是怎么做妓女
You know, just how to be.
你知道她过去几周
You got any idea where she might
在哪儿呆着吗
have been staying the last few weeks?
不知道
I don't.
她前男友在牢里
Her ex is in prison.
我猜她搬去了新的地方
I guess maybe she got a new place.
她还去教堂
She'd been going to church.
我还在指望也许她重新做人了
I was hoping maybe she just turned things around.
我们要询问所有有可能认识她的人
We're gonna need to question any girls might have known her.
这个要求可不好办
That's a tougher ask than you think.
人们听见你们来了  都躲得远远的
Folks'll be stayin' away, they hear y'all are out here.
女士  可这是把我们打发走的最好方法
Well, ma'am, it's the best way to get us to leave.
你说她留下了一个包
You said she left a bag.
对
Yeah.
我能看看吗
Can I see it?
当然
Sure.
那个女孩还没成人
That girl's not 18.
治安官知道你这里有未成年人吗
The sheriff know you got underage working here?
你知道这个女孩在哪儿呆过
What do you know about where that girl's been,
从哪儿来的吗
where she come from?
你想知道在她从她叔叔身边逃走之前
You want to know Beth's situation,
过得是什么样的日子吗
'fore she ran out on her uncle?
她还有其它地方可以去
There are other places she could go.
你说的这是屁话
Such holy bullshit from you.
那是女人自己的身体  不是吗
It's a woman's body, ain't it?
女人自己的选择
A woman's choice.
对我来说  她还不算个女人呢
Well, she don't look like a woman to me.
这种年龄  她根本没能力
At that age, she is not equipped
做这种选择
to make those kind of choices.
但我猜只要能赚钱  你才不管
But I guess you don't give a shit what kind of damage
她怎么伤害自己呢
she's doing to herself, as long as you're making your money.
这世界上有多少姑娘被白白糟蹋
Girls walk this Earth all the time screwin' for free.
现在你凭什么来搅合
Now, why is it you add business to the mix,
你这样的男人居然说承受不了
and boys like you can't stand the thought?
我来告诉你原因
I'll tell you.
因为突然间  你失去了
It's 'cause suddenly you don't own it
你以为自己拥有的东西
the way you thought you did.
女士  你们给予了很大帮助
Ma'am, you've both been very helpful.
我们保持联系
We'll be in touch.
是的  感谢...
Yes, thank you...
你的帮助
for your help.
去找找其他工作
Do something else.
那是订金吗
That a down payment?
你工作的其中一部分
Is shitting on any moment of decency
就是要把体面贬损得体无完肤吗
part of your job description?
我闭上眼睛  看到
"I closed my eyes and saw the king
身穿黄袍的国王正穿越树林
in yellow moving through the forest."
这是她的日记  马蒂
This is her diary, Marty.
真不敢相信
Believe this shit.
这么年轻的姑娘
A girl that young.
你知道吗  治安官也会抽一份利
You know the sheriff has got a stake in this place, too.
见鬼的耶稣
Fucking Christ.
国王的孩子都有印记
"The king's children were marked.
他们会变成他的天使
They became his angels."
黄袍国王  卡寇莎
The yellow king, Carcosa.
疯话
Nut job.
无论她在做什么  都把她弄疯了
Fried her brain on whatever she was on.
听着没头没尾的
Sounds like she didn't have much to begin with.
读起来好像一种幻想
Well, it reads like a fantasy.
会不会是他正给她用药
What if he was dosing her regular,
一段时间之后  在她无法察觉的情况下
and over a period of time, upping the dose
一点一点增加剂量
little by little without her knowing it?
我们应该四处检查一下
We should stay out here today, check around
看有没有路人认识她
for Johns maybe knew her.
你是否迷失  孤独  耶稣会拯救你
看这个
Look at this.
是的
Oh, yeah.
这有很多类似的活动
Man, a lot of these type places.
想吸引人来  然后游说他们
Expect the flock to canvass for 'em.
我们应该去看看
You know, we should go there.
崇拜团回归  现在还不晚  耶稣复活的伙伴们
可能是大家一直提起的那个教堂
Could be the church everyone mentioned.
先在外面跟路人打听打听
Well, let's check around for Johns while we're out here
然后周一去这座教堂
and pick up the church on Monday.
你的很多材料都是被修改过的
Most of your stuff's still redacted.
那么北岸是指什么
Now, what's Northshore?
北岸精神病院
Northshore Psychiatric Hospital,
德克萨斯州  拉伯克
Lubbock, Texas.
1993年我在那住了四个月
I spent 4 months there in '93.
-想说说这个吗    -没问题
- You feel like talking about that?   - Well, sure.
我才不在乎
Who gives a shit?
索菲亚  我女儿
Sofia... my daughter.
她在我家车道上骑小三轮车
She was on her tricycle in our driveway. Um...
我们住的地方  那条小路有点弯曲
We lived down a -- where a little bend in the road, and...
他们说
They said that...
总之  然后
Anyway, afterwards, uh,
克莱尔和我反目成仇了
Claire and I turned on each other, you know?
我们互相抱怨死的为什么不是对方
We... we resented each other being alive, you know?
我从劫案组转到扫毒组
I transferred from robbery to narco.
我就开始每天24小时  每周7天地做这些事
Started hitting it, you know, 24/7.
在街上搜刮  破门而入  三个月后
Street rips, knocking down doors, and within 3 months
我就该抢劫快递员  或者在华美达酒店醒过来
I was ripping off couriers or ending up in a Ramada Inn
身边一堆该死的八球[毒品]
with a couple of fuckin' eight-balls.
没错
Oh, yeah.
就是那时  克莱尔走了
Somewhere in there, Claire left,
也是那时
and somewhere in there,
我把满膛子弹打在了一个瘾君子身上
I emptied a 9 into a crankhead
因为他要给他襁褓中的女儿注射冰毒
for injecting his infant daughter with crystal.
他说要净化他女儿
Said he was trying to purify her.
检察官给了我一次机会  免于进监狱
State attorney gave me one chance to stay out of jail.
他说  我们可以让你的资料不受影响
He said, "You can keep your profile,
但我们想让你做我们的瘾君子线人
but we want to make you our wild man junkie."
他们说到做到  把我弄回了街上
So they did. They made me a floater, like a trick.
你懂得  所有探员
You know, any agency or
或部门都需要有一个深度卧底的缉毒警
department needed a deep undercover narco,
他们选中了我
they got me,
而且没有刑满的那一天
and there was no fuckin' expiration date, baby.
他们让你做了四年线人对吧
And they kept you out there for 4 years?
1993年2月
And then, February of '93,
我在休斯顿港杀了三个贩毒集团的人
I killed 3 cartel men in Port Houston.
我被判了三个25年徒刑  最后
I took three 25s in the side and ended up
被送进了德州拉伯克的北岸精神病院
at Northshore Psychiatric Hospital in Lubbock, Texas,
这本身就够好笑的了
which is kind of funny in its own rite--
在德州拉伯克精神病院
psych ward being in Lubbock, Texas. Heh!
你去过吗  他们还要给我精神病抚恤金
You ever been there? They offered me a psych pension.
算是中奖了  对吧
Jackpot, right?
但我拒绝了
And I said no.
我说  把我调到凶杀组吧
I said, "Put me on homicide somewhere."
他们欠了我不少人情
By then, I was owed quite a few favors,
所以  就把我调到路易斯安那来了
and, uh, Louisiana was what they had.
是啊  那之后好长时间
Yeah, for a long time after,
我都睡不好
I -- I didn't really sleep.
噩梦  创伤后应激障碍  身心俱疲什么的
Nightmares, PTSD, exhausted nerves, whatever.
没错
Yeah.
为什么要到凶杀组
Why homicide?
跟我在北岸看到的事有关
Oh, something I saw at Northshore.
柯林斯原话是这么说的
Quote from Corinthians.
"一体分离成众人"
"The body is not one member, but many."
"众人汇聚成一体"
"Now are they many, but... of one body."
那是什么意思
What's that mean, though?
我只是想在这个群体中保有一席之地
I was just trying to stay a part of the body now.
这根鱼竿坏掉了
The fishing pole's not working.
-那就去找爷爷    -才不要
- Just ask Grandpa.   - No.
爷爷  我不知道这根鱼竿好不好用
Grandpa, I can't tell if it's working.
亲爱的  等鱼咬钩了你就知道了
You'll know, honey. It'll yank at you hard.
-好吧    -你怎么不...
- Okay.   - Why don't you...
案子查的怎么样了  那个大案子
How's that case going? The big one?
还在查
Working it, you know.
我年轻时这种事可不常发生
Things like that didn't happen these parts when I was young.
人们嘴边挂着"女士""先生"
People said "Ma'am" And "Sir."
一家人总是聚在一起
Families stayed together.
那都是过去时光了
Yeah, that's how it was, huh?
也不都是
Not all the time.
过去的人更看重面子
There was more dignity.
没人会走上大街  嚷嚷着要权利
Everyone wasn't out in the street, yelling about their rights.
要是真的那么好
Well, if things were so great,
他们也不会想要改变了
they never would have changed.
什么事都没有
Nothing is going on.
我只是告诉你  要是出了什么事
I'm just saying, if there's a problem,
你可以找我谈谈
you can talk to me. You know that.
要是我跟谁闹了矛盾
If I have a problem with someone,
我会跟那些人谈的  妈妈
I talk to them, Ma.
你也应该能跟我谈谈
Well, you should be able to talk to me.
我知道婚姻是什么滋味
I know what it's like to be married to a man.
你以为男人都一个德行吗
You think they're all the same, huh?
我不明白为什么你对我如此粗鲁
I don't know why you're so rude to me.
你在外面受气  别冲我发火
If you're frustrated, don't take it out on me.
我觉得你该把电视修好
I think that you need to get your cable fixed
少把我往狗血肥皂剧里套
and stop confusing me with your soap operas.
你是在搅和无法掌控的事
Well, you beat up on what you can't control.
让周围的人都跟你遭殃
Makes it bad for everybody else.
-我不会用    -关我屁事  自己摆弄去
- I don't know how.   - I don't care. Just try.
-你给我弄    -我不管
- You do it.   - I can't.
你手比较小
You have smaller fingers.
梅茜  你就自己来吧
Macie, just do it.
你觉得这个世界没有变糟
So you're telling me the world isn't getting worse?
现在的孩子  一身黑衣服
I seen kids today, all in black,
浓妆艳抹  脸上涂得不成人样
wearing makeup, shit on their faces.
满口黄腔
Everything's sex.
还有克林顿
Clinton.
回顾历史
You know, throughout history,
我敢打赌所有老一辈都说过同样的话
I bet every old man probably said the same thing.
老一辈死了之后
And old men die,
世界依旧向前发展
and the world keeps spinning.
-姑娘们怎么样了    -我找到了一条线索
- How are the girls?   - I got this lead--
我找到了一条线索  我要去查查看
I got this lead I wanted to check up on.
我跟你说起过
I told you about it.
-你父亲可以送你回去    -不要
- Maybe your dad could bring you back.   - No.
你根本就没跟我说过
You didn't tell me anything about it.
这可是家庭聚会
This is a family day.
我真的跟你说起过
I did tell you about it.
我提起过  是那个新案子
I mentioned it. It's the new case.
好吧  那我们一起回去吧
Okay, well, how about we all head back, then?
好  亲爱的
Hmm. All right, sweetheart.
上岸吧  我们回家了
Come on! Let's go!
我的钓鱼线都缠到一起了
My line's tangled.
快把船划回来
Just paddle in.
-好吧    -我说了吧
- Okay.   - Told you!
多谢下午的招待
Thanks for the lovely afternoon.
谢谢你们
Thank you.
下午好  先生
Afternoon, sir.
-您好  警官    -我想问你个问题
- How you doing today, Officer?   - I have a question for you.
你见过这个女孩吗
You ever seen this girl?
从没见过她吗
You never seen her before?
-从没见过    -在这没见过
- Never before.   - Hm-mmm, not here.
问个问题
Question.
我在找这个女士  你认识她吗
I'm looking for this young lady. You recognize her?
给点"提示"会比较好
I might need a memory jog.
她叫朵拉  很年轻  金发
Dora. Young blonde?
朵拉  朵拉  朵拉  朵拉  朵拉
Dora. Dora, Dora, Dora, Dora.
朵拉
Dora.
最近有没有哪个男人
Have any guys come around lately,
来这不只是找乐子那么简单
looking for anything more than a good time?
再给你点钱你能想起点别的吗
You might be able to remember for a little more money?
也许吧
I might.
是吗
You might?
这么多年了
Years we've been through this.
亲爱的  听我说
Sweetheart, listen to me.
我只想跟你们在一起
There is nowhere else I want to be.
你可能都没意识到自己在撒谎
I wonder if you even know you're lying.
得了吧
Oh, come on!
我每天
Bad enough,
都要面对一堆烂事  已经够糟的了
the shit I got to wade through on a daily basis,
连上了三十小时的班  好不容易到了周末
bring me this "Feel bad for me" crap
却要听你爸爸放屁  你还给我一脸
when I work 30 hours straight and spent the weekend
"我真惨"的表情
listening to your dad's bullshit?
我回家  家应该是一个
I come home, the one place
充满祥和宁静的地方
where there's supposed to be peace and calm,
-你却让我去听...    -谁跟你说的
- and you throw this shit...   - Who told you that?
家并不总是那样的  也不该是那样
It's not always that way. It's not supposed to be.
那本该是我想要的  那本该帮助我
It's supposed to be what I want, it's supposed to help me.
我们就是在帮助你
We do help you!
一直如此
All the goddamn time!
好吧  你想让我说什么
Okay, well, what do you want me to say?
你想让我谈谈那个 有鹿角的女人吗
You want me to talk about the woman, had antlers?
你想让我跟你谈谈那些消失的孩子吗
Do you want me to tell you about the kids disappearing,
那样你就能不再发牢骚说自己有多惨了吗
and maybe you'll stop with the "poor me" little whiny bullshit?
你觉得我是这个意思吗
Is that what you're saying, hmm?
你觉得我是想让你觉得我有多惨
That I'm trying to make you feel bad for me?
你真这么认为吗
Is that really how you want to play this?
不  亲爱的
No, honey.
我觉得你是我见过的最好的女人
I think you're the greatest woman I ever met,
遇见你是我人生最美妙的事
and you're the greatest thing that ever happened to me.
但是  真的  有时候
But, yeah, you know, sometimes
我觉得你好像很容易
I think you might have a penchant
自怨自艾
for self-pity.
而现在  我希望你坚强一点
And right now, I need you to be strong
让我好做自己的工作
so that I can do my job.
你现在患上了选择性失聪
You have developed some sort of selective deafness.
你以前可不是这种懦夫
You used to not be such a chicken shit, I swear.
连你妈都觉得你很难缠
Even your mom thinks you're a ball-buster.
去叫孩子们来吃饭
Tell the girls dinner.
你失去爸爸或妈妈了
You don't have a mommy or daddy anymore.
他[她]在事故中死了
Yours just died in an accident.
怎么死的
How?
车祸  有人…
In a car accident. Someone--
吃晚饭了  孩子们  去厨房吧
Dinnertime, kids. Go to the kitchen.
你来吃吗
Are you coming?
当然  我都快饿死了
Yeah, of course. I'm starving.
真的吗
Really?
-真的    -太好了
- Yeah, really.   - Good.
你知道我现在是怎么想我女儿的吗
You know how I think about my daughter now?
你知道吗
You know what...
那些她没遭受的折磨
what she was spared?
有时我很庆幸
Sometimes I feel grateful.
医生们说
Doctors said
她当时毫无感觉
she didn't feel a thing.
直接昏迷了
Went straight into a coma,
然后  在那片黑暗中的…
and then, somewhere in that...
某一处  她悄无声息地离开了
blackness, she slipped off into another,
去了更深沉的黑暗中
deeper kind.
这种死法不是很美吗
Isn't that a beautiful way to go out?
毫无痛苦
Painlessly,
就是个快乐的孩子
as a happy child.
以后才死的麻烦就在于…
Yeah, trouble with...
你已经长大了
dying later is you've already grown up.
伤害已经造成  太晚了
Damage is done. It's too late.
你有孩子吗
You got kids?
你们必须足够
Well, you got the hubris
自大
it must take to...
才会从虚无中凭空找来一个灵魂
yank a soul out of nonexistence
塞到孩子的肉体中
into this meat.
并让一条生命受困于此
And to force a life into this thresher.
至于我女儿  她…
And as for my daughter, she, uh...
她让我免遭为人父的
she spared me the sin
罪孽
of being a father.
凯思琳
Hey, Cathleen,
你个小狐狸精
you little vixen.
能给我来点咖啡吗
Any chance of some coffee?
-当然    -好吧
- Of course.   - Okay.
这些人是谁
Who are these guys?
柯萨达带来的几个混球  咖啡马上来
Some assholes Quesada brought in. Coffee on its way.
早上好  马蒂
Hey, morning, Marty.
组长正在给我介绍新来的特警队
Major's introducing me. New flying squad.
你认识马克·多特里  泰德·贝特朗
You know Mark Daughtry, Ted Bertrand.
多特里
Daughtry.
泰德
Ted.
-吉米·杜福伦    -吉米·杜福伦
- Jimmy Dufrene.   - Jimmy Dufrene.
怎么了
What's up?
我们接到任务
We've been tasked with
调查一些可能和灵异现象有关的犯罪
investigating crimes with possible occult links.
最近出现很多残害动物
There's been a rash of animal mutilations,
亵渎坟墓的行为
cemeteries defiled.
他们想看看我们在兰的案子上有什么发现
And they want to see what we have on the Lange case.
这项工作  局长
Well, this task force is important to the Commander
和州办公室都很重视
and to the Governor's Office.
你知道  很多人都关心这件事
You know, a lot of people are concerned about it.
我可看不出两只死猫和一个被杀女子之间
You know, me, I don't see the connection
有什么关系
between two dead cats and a murdered woman.
不过我是从德克萨斯来的
But then, I'm from Texas.
我们无意冒犯  马蒂
We're not stepping on your toes, Marty.
我们也只是听从命令
We just got the mandate.
我们要互相交换一下情报
We got to compare notes with what you got.
当然
Yeah.
给你咖啡  警探
Here you are, Detective.
-谢谢  凯思琳    -不客气
- Thanks, Cathleen.   - You got it.
把你们想要的都复印一份吧
Xerox all you want.
那你们就会觉得自己是个好警察了
Make you feel like good cops.
你们两个  来我办公室
You two, my office.
科尔  我定了个新规矩  特别是对你
Cohle, we got a new rule around here, especially for you.
当你对任何事有意见的时候
You got an opinion about anything,
别说出来
you hold on to it.
要么别说  要么就告诉马蒂
You hold on to it or you tell it to Marty.
否则就把你那张大嘴给我缝严实了
Otherwise, button your big, fat mouth.
不管你有多聪明  都没你想的那么聪明
However smart you are, you're not as smart as you think.
别扯淡了  头儿
Be serious, boss.
都是他妈的废话
This God-bothering shit.
那都是些政治套话  你懂的
It's a political circle-jerk. You know this.
这是你乱搞的地方吗
Is this a place you live?
你觉得你是在哪儿
Where are you, huh?
这几周你有进展吗  抓到嫌疑人了吗
You had anything in the last weeks? You got a suspect?
多给我们几个人
Give us some more guys
去跟踪重点对象  做记录
to follow up KAs, track records.
不  我们老板根本不想用你  明白吗
No, our bosses don't want you at all, you understand?
我也不想用你
I don't want you.
你能在这儿完全是因为这个人的信誉担保
You are upright only by the grace of this man's reputation.
该死的  科尔
Goddamn, Cohle.
我还得说什么才能让你他妈闭嘴啊
How many ways are there for me to say, "Shut the fuck up"?
我们要服从命令  不是吗
I mean, we work under command, right?
现在我们的上司要我们公开  高调的回应
Now, our betters want a public, high-profile show of response.
妈的  现在有个参议员
Shit, I got a state senator,
非要把那撒旦式涂鸦当作仇恨犯罪
he's trying to label Satanic graffiti as a hate crime.
这跟我们的数据库没有关系  这是事实
That has nothing to do with our DB, and that's the fact of it.
好吧  好吧  行
Okay, okay. Fine.
就算是真的  行吗
Let's say that's true, all right?
就算让你们全权负责这个案子
Let's say that you guys get the case all to yourselves.
你有过调查一件谋杀案一周以上还一无所获吗
You ever solve a murder, been in the red more than a week?
有过一个案子不是
You ever clear one where two rounds
两轮审问之后就乖乖招了的吗
of questions didn't hand you the fucking answer?
-拜托    -你们有线索  有时间线
- Oh, come on--   - No, no, you got leads, you got a timeline.
你知道我有什么吗  我有一本侦探小说
You know what I got? I got a whodunit
写着我的两个警探无所作为
where my two detectives are stalling,
还有一个新的特别小组想接手这案子
and I got a brand-new task force wants to take it off our hands.
我们有个线索
We have a lead--
看在上帝的份上  闭嘴  科尔
Oh, for Christ's sake. Fuck off, Cohle.
上帝
Christ.
你决定吧
It's your call.
你想放弃这个案子吗
You want to dump this one off?
鉴于公众的反应  我会考虑下的
You know, I'd think about it, given the spotlight.
泰德·贝特朗是个好警探  你知道他的
You know, Teddy Bertrand's a good detective. You know him.
你就算闭上嘴还是个自以为是的家伙
Well, you're a smart-ass with your mouth shut.
我只是想说
I was just gonna say
我们有一条线索指向一个教堂
we've got a lead on a church.
被害人在那里呆了很长时间
Our vic was spending a lot of time there.
我们现在正要去调查这个  可能是个突破点
That's where we were headed. It could be the break we need.
这么说  不管他们做什么
Inside, whatever they're putting over you,
你还能为我们争取多少时间
how much more time could you get us?
现在不好说  还有得谈  但是
Right now, it's up for discussion, but,
塔特尔在火上浇油
you know, Tuttle's lighting a fire under this.
没有嫌疑犯  他们就会
Without a suspect, they're just gonna
不问问题直接下命令了  马蒂
stop asking questions, Marty, and they're gonna give orders.
就这样
That's that.
给我们点时间  这个月之内吧
Give us the rest of the month
趁着他们还没把这个案子归结成
before they lump it into whatever
什么特别小组需要的鬼样子  行吗
the play is with the task force, yeah?
我尽量
I'll try.
两周时间  然后你们就继续上街抓人去吧
Two weeks, and then you two start catching again.
好
Yeah.
我们直奔主题吧
Let's cut to the point.
说白了  你们就是想问
As the crow flies, y'all are wanting to ask
树林里的那场大败  对吧
about that big throwdown in the woods, yeah?
最后会问的  当然
Eventually, sure.
现在我们只是想追查这个案子
Right now, we're just trying to track the case.
特别是科尔如何解决的
How Cohle worked it, especially.
说明你们认为我粗枝大叶到意识不到
Which indicates you think I'm too thick to realize
你们是想找人麻烦
that y'all are trying to jam somebody up.
你们之前肯定没遇到过这种情况
You're on to something new.
所以科尔不想把案子移交给特别小组
So Cohle didn't want to give it to the task force.
你呢
Did you?
不  我也不想
No, I did not.
这没道理  这里什么都没有
It don't make sense. There is nothing out here.
按照地图  应该就在几公里之内
According to this map, it should be within these few miles.
耶稣会拯救你
如果是那种临时性的
Well-- ahem-- I guess if it's one of those
开信仰复兴布道会的地方  会经常迁移的
tent revival places, they move around.
是啊
Yeah.
临时场所经常这样
Tents usually do.
这张传单上没有日期  很奇怪
There's no date on this flyer, which is strange.
那是什么
Something up there.
等等  上一句
Wait, wait, back up.
你是说你在工作时产生了幻觉
Are you saying you were hallucinating on the job?
不  我是说  我可以
No. I mean, I could always
区别开什么是真实的什么不是
tell what was real or what wasn't, you know.
所以当我产生幻觉的时候  我就会顺其自然
So when I'd see things, like, man, I'd just-- -- roll with it.
你现在还会产生幻觉
You still see things?
不会了
No.
不  在我戒毒的几年之后
No, they stopped altogether
就彻底消失了
after I was clean a couple years.
这个地方没有门牌号
No numbers on this place.
火灾肯定发生在很久之前
Fire must have happened a long time ago.
好吧  这个地方毁了
Okay. Place is trashed.
什么东西都没有了
This ain't no kinda anything.
在那个时候  那些异象
Yeah, back then, the visions.
大多数时候  我都确信不会再有了
Yeah, most of the time, I was convinced that I'd lost it.
马蒂
Marty?
但还有些时候
But there were other times...
我觉得自己仍沉溺于探索宇宙的神秘真相之中
I thought I was mainlining the secret truth of the universe.
--==本字幕由 HDWinG字幕组 荣誉出品==--